Jewel James

Mobile No: <u>+61-476675582</u> | Email: <u>jeweljames1992@gmail.com</u> | Portfolio: jeweljames.info | Linkedin id: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamjewel/ |

Summary

Experienced Data Consultant with 3+ years of track record of analysing business intelligence reports and data that are extracted from different sources in the retail domain. Handling multiple clients requirements and formulating a plan of action. Proven knowledge in expanding existing data collection and maintaining high quality data standards. Worked extensively in development reports and maintenance of analytical projects using Python, Java, SQL and PowerBI tools.

Skills

Data Science - Data Preprocessing, Data Visualization, Machine Learning (Intermediate), Deep Learning, Time Series Forecasting, Tableau, Dashboarding.

Business Analytics - Decision Modelling, What-If analysis, Trend analysis, Variance analysis.

Programming Languages - Python, R and Java

Database Management Systems - SQL, and MongoDB

Cloud Computing - Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform

Microsoft software tools - Excel (VBA, VLOOKUP, and Pivot tables), PowerPoint, and Word

Experience

Amazon | Business Intelligence Analyst

Jul 2015 - Aug 2018

- + Extracted and cleaned data from reports, databases, etc and applied different text mining techniques using Python and SQL scripting.
- + Delivered huge volumes of data with granular level accuracy within strict deadlines. (100 Million+ rows of data)
- + Executed successful migration and reporting of **key metrics** derived from data handled by the expansion team.
- + Identified the valuable information within the unstructured data and transformed it in a tabulated form which can enable further analysis.
- + Performed descriptive and prescriptive analysis on retail data for a customer profiling.
- + Developed a reporting tool for showing valuable information to the stakeholders.
- + Communicated reports and work completed with project stakeholders
- + Contributed significantly to the **Product Compatibility Platform** team, which made an incremental turnover of **\$9 Million** in 2015.
- + Review of daily status updates and tracking of the analysts.
- + Experience of taking over 25+ technical interview rounds.
- + Contributed significantly to the **Product Compatibility Platform** team, which made an incremental turnover of **\$9 Million** in 2015.

SarasCare | Data Science Intern

March 2021 - July 2021

- + Formulated the problems statement such that it should add value to the business.
- + Developed and deployed python-flask based web application(chatbot) from scratch.
- + Figured out the advantages and limitations of examined models and made decisions on which model to implement in production.
- + Applied NLP model to the dataset for predicting the severity of the cases.
- + Implementation of Open AI GPT 3 ,SimCSE Bert and the Crude Classifier model.
- + Figuring out the future scope, advantages and limitations of examined models.
- + Developed and deployed python-flask based web application(chatbot).
- + Deployed application in Microsoft Azure as per client requirement.

180 Degree Consultancy | Consultant

March 2021 - July 2021

- + Provided client with information regarding partnership opportunities in interstate youth career counselling programs.
- + Collaborated with team members and client to dissect and analyze project requirements.
- + Communicated complex insights in a persuasive manner via data visualization and professional pitches.
- + Adopted the Design Thinking approach (and implemented User Story and Journey Maps) to understand key stakeholders' wants and needs.
- + Delivered a professional business pitch to the client representatives and industry partners.
- + Quality control and compilation of deliverables with final reports presented to client.

Projects

Stance Classification in Tweets - Sentiment Analysis

Link - https://github.com/jamjewel/Stance-Classification-in-Tweets-using-NLP

This project was undertaken to do stance classification of tweets and discover the best fitting deep learning model that can successfully classify stance (FAVOR, AGAINST, NONE) based on a particular Target (topic) about a tweet. Final selection was made of the LSTM model as they proved to work best in natural language processing scenarios. The model after large iterations of fine tuning made it robust and provided an accuracy score on validation as 52.97 and test score as 53.8 respectively.

Classify Images of Road Traffic Signs - Deep Learning

Link - https://github.com/jamjewel/Classify-Images-of-Road-Traffic-Signs

This project was undertaken to discover the best fitting machine learning model which can successfully classify images based on two factors, namely shape and labels. Three different ML model development techniques were employed: MLP, CNN. The CNN model proved to be highly accurate. Analysis of intra variability of classes and comparison of classification performance of four Convolutional Neural Networks based on parameter tuning gave us the optimal model. The images provided are grey scaled and sized to a 28*28 density. The development of the model has three stages: image preprocessing, detection, and recognition. The model demonstrated a promising result with an accuracy of 81 %for shape classification and 62% for label classification. Independent evaluation was done by collecting images from internet sources and real time clicks of Victorian, Melbourne streets.

Covid -19 Analytics Web App - Cloud Computing

Link - https://github.com/jamjewel/covidanalytics

Developed an application using Amazon web services and extends a Web system to add business functionality. The environmental setup was done using elastic beanstalk where the backend was developed using NodeJs. The virtual server was launched through the EC2 instance and NoSQL database mongo DB was used for data storage. A complete user profile authentication was set up using amazon cognito.

Grant Procurement / Brand Uplifting - Business Consultancy

The main objective of this project is to identify and evaluate which of the key segments (Disability, Refugees, Councils, ATSI, Mental Health, Youth OOHC and Forensic) currently provide the largest source of funding to CEAV Careers Counselling Australia. This objective was to be achieved through analysing and synthesising the information about grants/programs in each segment, collating the data and generating insights that could help CEAV secure the funding. The expectation was that this would help CEAV to better position themselves to gain funding opportunities .

Education

Masters of Data Science - (Future Leaders Scholarship) Feb 2019 - Jul 2021
RMIT University

Bachelors of Technology (Computer Science and Engineering)

Jul 2011 - Jun 2015

Anna University

Referees

Available on request.